Finding Aid for Frank B. Woodford papers, 1940-1967
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Frank B. Woodford papers 1940-1967
Woodford, Frank B. (Frank Bury), 1903-1967.
86390 Aa 2
Detroit, Michigan journalist and historian. Correspondence, speeches, scrapbooks, book reviews and manuscripts of unpublished writings; also research materials concerning Lewis Cass, Augustus B. Woodward, Gabriel Richard, and Alexander J. Groesbeck, and papers relating to the Civil War in Michigan, the development of Harper Hospital in Detroit, Michigan, the Detroit Public Library, the Detroit Free Press, and the building of the Mackinac Bridge.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
3 linear feet
The collection was the gift of Frank B. Woodford.(donor no. 3449 )
Periodic additions to the records are not expected.
The collection is open to research.
Frank B. Woodford was born in Detroit on Feb. 27, 1903, and was educated at Hillsdale College and the University of Pennsylvania. He joined the staff of the Detroit Free Press as a reporter in 1931, became an assistant city editor a few years later, and became an editorial writer in 1944. He was named the paper's chief editorial writer in 1956. He was appointed in 1961 to the paper's editorial board. He retired from the newspaper in 1962.
Woodford was also a historian, authoring nine books on Michigan history. These volumes included biographies of Lewis Cass, Justice Augustus B. Woodward, and Michigan Governor Alexander J. Groesbeck, and histories of the Detroit Public Library and Harper Hospital in Detroit.
In addition to writing books and producing editorials for the Detroit Free Press, Woodford was a frequent contributor in the nineteen-forties to the News of the Week in Review Section of The Sunday New York Times.
He died June 19, 1967.
The Frank B. Woodford papers consist of correspondence, speeches, scrapbooks, book reviews and manuscripts of unpublished writings; also research materials concerning Lewis Cass, Augustus B. Woodward, Gabriel Richard, and Alexander J. Groesbeck, and papers relating to the Civil War in Michigan, the development of Harper Hospital in Detroit, Michigan, the Detroit Public Library, the Detroit Free Press, and the building of the Mackinac Bridge. The collection is organized into four series: Correspondence; Writings and related material; Scrapbooks and newspaper clippings; and Other materials.
Subjects:
American newspapers--Michigan--Detroit.; Bridges.; Cass, Lewis, 1782-1866.; Detroit (Mich.); Detroit Free Press.; Detroit Public Library.; Groesbeck, Alexander J. (Alexander Joseph), 1873-1953.; Harper Hospital.; Historians--Michigan--Detroit.; Hospitals--Michigan--Detroit.; Journalists--Michigan--Detroit.; Mackinac Bridge Authority (Mich.); Richard, Gabriel, 1767-1832.; United States--History--Civil War, 1861-1865.; Woodward, Augustus B. (Augustus Brevoort), d. 1827.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Bookstores--Michigan.; Woodford, Frank B. (Frank Bury), 1903-1967.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.; Scrapbooks.
- Correspondence
  - Undated 1953-1967, 9 folders (Box 1)
- Writings and related material
  - Correspondence relating to "Mr. Jefferson's Disciple-A Life of Justice A.B. Woodward" by Frank Woodford 1953 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning "Gabriel Richard, Frontier Ambassador" by Frank Woodford and Albert Hyma 1956-1957 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning "Mighty Mac, The Picture History of the Mackinac Bridge" by Lawrence A. Rubin, plus manuscript of the introduction by Frank Woodford 1958 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning "Father Abraham's Children; Michigan Episodes in the Civil War" 1958-1962 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning "Alex J. Groesbeck: Portrait of a Public Man" by Frank Woodford, plus photocopy of the introduction by Roscoe O. Bonisteel 1960-1962 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning "Harper of Detroit, The Origin and Growth of a Great Metropolitan Hospital" by Frank Woodford and Philip Mason 1962-1964 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning "Parnassus on Main Street" by Frank Woodford 1963-1967 (Box 1)
  - Speeches and press releases, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning Free Press History Book undated (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning article on Lewis Cass in Encyclopedia Americana, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Paper entitled "The Great Guns of Erie" undated (Box 1)
- Scrapbooks and newspaper clippings
  - Scrapbook containing Detroit Free Press articles, 1942 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook containing Detroit Free Press articles, 1949-1951 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook containing reviews of his books 1950 (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook containing Detroit Free Press articles, 1952-1955 (Box 2)
  - Newspaper clippings August 1940-1950, 11 folders (Box 2)
- Other materials
  - Book reviews, awards, and clippings (Box 3)
  - Book reviews (Box 3)
  - Papers concerning book contracts 1960-1963 (Box 3)
  - Papers concerning appointment as historiographer of Detroit 1966-1967 (Box 3)
  - Miscellanea (Box 3)
  - Printed miscellanea (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of "Coeur de Lion, The Story of Richard I of England" (Box 3)
  - Manuscript of "Valorous Encounter" (Box 3)
  - Photographs: portraits, photos of Woodford at a book signing, and photos of Woodford at historical commemorations (Box 3)